Patrick Larson

Software Engineer

github.com/patrickslarson8 • linkedin.com/in/patrick-larson8

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

I am a software engineer with one year of experience complemented with seven years of military service. have an additional two years of experience coding for personal projects. My career made me a driven problem solver with excellent communication and collaboration skills. I place people first and believe everything else comes second. My education includes studying electrical engineering, computer hardware, and most recently artificial intelligence.

SELECTED ACCOMPLISHMENTS

- Al Project using computer vision to autonomously plug in an electric vehicle
 - Skills Leveraged: Python | TensorFlow | Computer Vision | Linux OS
- Developed and maintained database application to track the progress of students through Army Aviation flight school, streamlining the administrative workflow
 - Skills Leveraged: SQL | Visual Basic | MS Access
- Airport Check-in Queuing Simulation to study the principles of Object-Oriented Programming
 - Skills Leveraged: C++ | OOP
- Desktop application project to manage classes, students, and teachers of an organization to learn the fundamentals of C#
 - Skills Leveraged: C# | SQL | OOP
- Personal website (patrickslarson8.github.io) to learn frontend and web fundamentals
 - Skills Leveraged: HTML | CSS | JavaScript

CERTIFICATIONS

- TensorFlow Developer (ID: 56236042)
- Azure Data Science Associate (ID: 994164510)

EXPERIENCE

OCT 2022 – PRESENT MICROSOFT – SOFTWARE AND SYSTEMS ACADEMY

REMOTE

- Competitive and rigorous computer science fundamentals program
- Training in skills including C#, T-SQL, Algorithms, Data Structures, OOP, HTML5, ASP.Net, and Git

OCT 2021 – OCT 2022 U.S. ARMY – SOFTWARE ENGINEER

FORT RUCKER, AL

- Developed and deployed student tracking database with continuous support through bug fixes and feature implementation
- Worked outside scope to streamline outdated workflows by developing SharePoint sites

JAN 2020 – OCT 2021 U.S. ARMY – DOCTRINE INSTRUCTOR

FORT RUCKER, AL

- Trained and mentored over 700 students of diverse backgrounds in my tenure
- Certified in Army Equal Opportunity and Resilience programs
- Improved curriculum by updating doctrine and techniques with great attention to detail

JAN 2017 – JAN 2020 U.S. ARMY – HELICOPTER PLATOON LEADER

FORT HOOD, TX

- Routinely deployed and maintained networks of computers in mission-critical roles, reducing planning and mission response times
- Managed customer success and translated requirements by integrating aviation operations into unfamiliar units
- Continuously multi-tasked while organizing the daily operations of 40 personnel and flight operations including 350 flights and 1,400 flight hours with a 0% failure rate

MAY 2015 – JAN 2017 U.S. ARMY – HELICOPTER FLIGHT SCHOOL

FORT RUCKER, AL

• Trained and certified in the Boeing CH-47F cargo helicopter

EDUCATION

Jan 2022 – Present

Whiting School of Engineering at Johns Hopkins University

BALTIMORE, MD

- Master of Science in Artificial Intelligence
 Anticipated completion Summer 2024
- 4.0 in related coursework

Jul 2011 – May 2015 United States Military Academy

WEST POINT, NY

- Bachelor of Science in Electrical Engineering
- Focus on computer hardware and networking fundamentals
- Competed in an inaugural NSA-sponsored network security competition